<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PMRF Annual review: 2021 on Himadree Das</title>
    <link>http://about.kakati.email/himadree/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PMRF Annual review: 2021 on Himadree Das</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 17:53:30 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://about.kakati.email/himadree/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Area of Research</title>
      <link>http://about.kakati.email/himadree/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://about.kakati.email/himadree/research/</guid>
      <description>My current research interests include:
 Biopolymer conjugates and nanomaterials for therapeutics. Biomaterials &amp;amp; Tissue Engineering Targeted Drug Delivery Systems/ delivery of antitumor agents Novel Biomaterials for environmental remediation  1. Graphene oxide and chitosan-based conjugated polymeric nanocomposite for the effective adsorption of heavy metal ions in water resources. Several domestic and industrial processes release heavy metals in the environment. The presence of heavy metals at water bodies and soils at elevated concentrations are not acceptable, as they result in health hazards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conferences Attended</title>
      <link>http://about.kakati.email/himadree/conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://about.kakati.email/himadree/conferences/</guid>
      <description>CEMS Topical Meeting Online Emergent Bioengineering Materials, September 1, 2021, RIKEN CEMS. Online workshop on Powder X-Ray Diffraction Techniques and its Applications. January 20 &amp;amp; 21, 2021, North East Centre for Biological Sciences and Healthcare Engineering (NECBH) Indian Institute of Technology Guwahati, Assam. Participated in Wiley Author Webinar Series “Learn to Publish” held in June-July 2020. Biotech hub skill development series (BSDS), 2018. MRD LifeSciences (P) Ltd. Institutional Biotech Hub Seminar on Careers in science and Biotechnology, 2018, Tezpur University, Assam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://about.kakati.email/himadree/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://about.kakati.email/himadree/contact/</guid>
      <description>Himadree Das Ph.D. Research Scholar,
Lab: CHEL-208; Bioorganic Chemistry Lab,
Centre For Environment, Indian Institute of Technology, Guwahati
Email: d.himadree@iitg.ac.in</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>http://about.kakati.email/himadree/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://about.kakati.email/himadree/education/</guid>
      <description>Ph.D. Research Scholar (December 2019 - Present)  Course Work: Completed (Course Details) Fellowship: Prime Minister&amp;rsquo;s Research Fellowship (May 2018 - Present)
Undergraduate and postgraduate (2013-2018) Tezpur University, Tezpur, Assam Department of Molecular Biology and Biotechnology</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>http://about.kakati.email/himadree/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://about.kakati.email/himadree/experience/</guid>
      <description>Online Teaching Assistant Dates Employed: Jan 2020 – Apr 2020 Employment Duration: 1 year
  MOOC Online course on &amp;quot; Essentials of Biomolecules: Nucleic Acids and Peptides Online Teaching Assistant Dates Employed: Jan 2021 – Apr 2021 Employment Duration: 4 months
  MOOC Online course on &amp;quot; Essentials of Biomolecules: Nucleic Acids and Peptides
  Junior research fellow: IIT Guwahati, under the supervision of Dr. Debashish Das, Department of BSBE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://about.kakati.email/himadree/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://about.kakati.email/himadree/publications/</guid>
      <description>  Horo, H., Saha, M., Das, H., Mandal, B. &amp;amp; Kundu, L. M. Synthesis of highly fluorescent, amine-functionalized carbon dots from biotin-modified chitosan and silk-fibroin blend for target-specific delivery of antitumor agents. Carbohydr. Polym. 277, 118862 (2022).
  Chitosan-derived biomaterials in cancer therapeutics and biomedical imaging. Himali Horo, Himadree Das, Gourav Bhattacharjee, Lal Mohan Kundu, , Book chapter (Submitted)
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
